Carson Bruce (Work in progress)

I am passionate when creating simple and beautiful apps.

I take interest in the entire software development process. Through from the start when a project is imagined towards its end as a project is released. I have experienced a range of roles and tasks covering its broad range.

I consider some of my key skills to include: Problem solving, Speed to learn, Openmindedness, Being a team player, and Communication.

I am a year-zero adopter of JavaScript technologies, Angular, React, Node.js, and Express, embracing the continuing shift towards simplier and more agile systems and process. I love working with JavaScript and all the technologies and process it enables.

Come say hi at hello@carson.kiwi

Experience

Solnet

Aug 2012 - Now (3.5 years)



I started Solnet a week out from graduating kicking off the role straight into the delivery team of the company. A year in I moved on over into the Digital team where my love for JavaScript and appreciation for UX boomed. I have gained experience with several high profile clients placed first as a developer along with other roles such as devops, ux, team lead, tech lead. More recently in my time at Solnet I have been involved in mentoring others in JavaScript tooling and practices. See the following Projects section for an overview of some of the work I've done at Solnet.

Research Project: Query Expansion

Nov 2011 - March 2012 (4 months)



My second research opportunity was offered by the supervisor of my honours project to further its report towards an end goal of a published research paper. With some give and take from the wider Web Intellegence team at Victoria I managed to get the paper submitted and accepted to an Australasian Web Intellegence conference by the end of my research.

Research Project: Eye Gaze tracking

Nov 2010 - March 2011 (4 months)



I was awarded a research scholarship at the end of my 300 level university year giving me experience in planning directing a research project. With support from my supervisor and his team, I contributed to development on an open source gaze tracking system helping it evolve to a level where it might benefit the university, saving an equivelant commercial product cost of \$10,000. In addition to learning about eye-tracking systems I gained experience in project practice and quickly learned C#.

Cool Bananas

Nov 2009 - March 2010 (4 months)

Interning with a fellow student alongside a senior software engineer I worked on a project developing a prototype scripting parser and runtime for embedded systems. The experience helped cement my years study learning C, Agile processes, and testing practices. The project proved successful gaining further funding being developed into a commercial product.

Education

Victoria University of Wellington

Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Software Engineering, First Class Honours *2007-2012*

Projects

Employment Agreement Builder

Ministry of Business and Innovation and Employment

EAB is a web application realised to provide value to both front end users along with those responsible for its maintenance. Small to medium business parties are able to use the tool to step through creating a new Employment agreement while at the same time educating themselves about employment law with easy to digest content and links. I lead the implementation design while mentoring a Senior Java developer transitioning to JavaScript. The project ran successfully meeting its internal and external objectives finishing in three months.

- Followed BDD and TDD development processes
- · Data driven forms
- Through and through Javascript client, server, test suite.
- Created a complete automation test suite covering close to all app features.
- Node.js micro services implementation
- Created a decoupled CMS component to support the application see cmeasy.herokuapp.com
- Created internal email, document, form components already reused on other projects
- Security implementation
- Performance profiling and reviews
- Automated testing and releases a dozen times a day
- Docker containerised environments handling node scaling, static servers and bringing deployment time down to seconds
- · Angular.js front end

NEON

Sky Television

- Time critical environment
- Collaberation with UX and design teams ensuring good usability of solution
- Presented UX and design solution alternatives to client
- Worked remotely for half the project

Online Banking

Westpac

- Tech leading and mentoring of a team five large
- Improved developer tooling and experience with features like livereload
- Created the Client and Middleware security feature
- · Middleware Javascript framework design, implementation, and testing
- Gatekeeper of critical environments used by a team of 60
- · Provided IBM Worklight and Backbone.js consulting
- Hybrid and webapp application design
- Performance profiling of application

Air Forms

Air New Zealand

- · Data driven forms
- Hybrid application design running on Supersonic
- Polished the application improving rendering performance and removing jank

Learning clients name game

Classified

We entered in a competition to imagine, design, and develop a proof of concept mobile gamification app in 3 days. Our UX and developer streams worked well together from the start, laying foundations for one another and we managed to create a complete working iOS game that would quiz the user on peoples names with multiple minigames supported by a global leaderboard. We placed well in the competition winning the prize of placing in the companies evaluation panel for future projects followed shortly after with a winning proposal for a separate project.

- Created a complete proof of concept application in 3 days
- Succeeded in gaining a position on the clients project panel
- Hybrid application design
- Worked efficently with other JavaScript, UX and UI developers

Employee Cost Calculator

Ministry of Business and Innovation and Employment

- Created proof of concept application as presales
- Contributed to the RFP solution design and estimates
- Designed and implemented Google Analytics solution
- Managed UAT test handover

Public website

Solnet

Full-stack javascript project Solo developer picking up JavaScript, CSS, HTML

- · Self managed team
- Collaberated closely with designer and UX roles
- HTML, CSS, JS development
- Implemented Node.js SEO and decoupled static content

ACC

Shared Capability

Little bite of javascript gave me the curse

- Java developer
- Quick learner
- Enterprise application environments
- Successfully integrated IBM Forms Experience Builder product with IBM Portal collaberating with IBM development team and providing development experience solutions

Skills - TODO

Interests - TODO

- Javascript
- User Experience
- Netball
- Running
- Cycling
- Photography
- Gaming
- Sound systems
- Beer brewing
- Stenciling

hello@carson.kiwi